Yi Liu

Web Developer

(613)252-8014 | <u>liuy2033@gmail.com</u> | <u>https://www.iamyiliu.com</u> https://github.com/yliu481 | www.linkedin.com/in/yliu481

SUMMARY

Hard-working Web Developer with experience in front-end development using ReactJS and back-end using NodeJS. Developed an E-commerce web app for a local company and a website for an educational institution. Passionate about Back-end development, also keep contributing to open source projects.

EXPERIENCES

Web Developer April 2020 – Present

Freelance

DPA GOLD https://dpagold.com/

- Maintained the company's Shopify website.
- Developed customized and reusable sections and Built new pages, boosted sales by 30%.

Zhong Jia Inc. http://www.waijiaomingshi.com

- Created company website for an educational institution, increased customers by 20%
- Deployed this website using Nginx.

Front End Developer

Jan 2019 - March 2020

AirMSMB Inc.

BizMSM https://github.com/yliu481/BizMSM-gif-demon

Tech stack: ReactJS, Material-UI, Jest, Django, Cordova, MySQL

- Worked in an agile team with 5 members to deliver a local E-commerce application that provides a possible solution for small businesses in their local area.
- Built reusable components and wrote unit-tests for performance and efficiency.
- Collaborated with team members using GitHub workflow.
- Designed and developed the shopping system and secure the transactions using Blockchain technology.

Research Assistant | Teaching Assistant

Jan 2019 - March 2020

Bell Research Lab, University of Ottawa

Blockchain verifier

Tech stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap3, PhoneGap, Blockchain

- Designed and built a standalone mobile app to verify blockchain transactions.
- Created a sorting function, for a better user experience.
- Converted it into an Android application using the PhoneGap framework.

PROJECT

Emaily https://github.com/yliu481/emaily

A web application that can send email surveys following the recipient's list.

Tech Stack: ReactJS, Express, MongoDB, Google OAuth, Strip, SendGrid

- Built a single-page application that consumes RESTful API from the backend.
- Built a backend using Express that consumes existing API from third parties.
- Used the Google OAuth for the user to easily login with Gmail, Stripe for payment, the SendGrid for sending email surveys.

Rental http://www.liuxubin.com

A web application that can evaluate rental based on some information.

Tech Stack: ReactJS, Python, Django, GCP, Docker, Nginx

- Built the frontend and backend, deployed it on Google Cloud Platform using Docker and Nginx.
- Used ReactJS for frontend, Django REST framework for backend API.

Easy Learn

Faculty of Information Technology, Beijing University of Chemical Technology

Tech stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap3, Python, Django, MySQL

- A platform for students to get course materials and find course-related tests.
- Designed and created an education assistant system for students to improve learning efficiency.

EDUCATION

University of Ottawa Sep 2018 – Mar 2020

Master of System Science

Beijing University of Chemical Technology Sep 2014 - Jun 2018

Bachelor of Automation

SKILLS

Language: Javascript ES6, HTML, CSS, Java, Python, SQL

Framework: ReactJS, Redux, Material-UI, JQuery, Django, Jest, Express

Database Management System: MySQL, MongoDB **Technology**: Git, Docker, Nginx, Cordova, Blockchain